# Mitren Chinoy

mitren@gmail.com :: 979-777-7513 :: @nertim

https://github.com/nertim :: https://linkedin.com/in/mitren :: https://twitter.com/nertim

#### Introduction

Full stack software developer with experience throughout the entire software life cycle from design to maintenance. Passionate about learning/teaching new concepts and mentoring junior devs. I am interested in pursing a career allowing me to guide a team of individuals to solve interesting technical challenges.

## Programming languages

Listed in the order of proficiency

- C#
- Javascript (family with Angular and React)
- HTML
- Python (mostly for fun/personal projects)
- CSS

## Experience

#### 2013 - Present: Microsoft

Senior Software Engineer

- Products worked on: Azure Monitoring (autoscale), Azure LogicApps, Azure WebApps, Azure FunctionApps
- Architect and developed experiences for the Azure Portal. Two of the largest ones are for WebApp creates and deployments.
- Worked with PMs, Customers, and Designers to re-design existing scenarios and design brand new scenarios.
- Worked on several data pipelines and automated reports. These reports provide targeted information to each team identifying issues in their layers.
- Actively engaged in the code review process to ensure consistency and optimal code.
- Maintained documentation and encouraged the team to help maintain.
- Mentored junior devs and interns.

### 2012 - 2013: Prognosis

Lead Software Developer

- Developed and maintained enterprise (Clinical and Financial solutions) EMR application for Hospitals and Clinics.
- Created a REST API generator based on the MS SQL database schemas.
- Ensured requirements for Meaning Use Stage 2 are researched and developed to meet 2014 deadline.
- Ensured requirements for Meaning Use Stage 1 by the Government are met allowing hospitals to attest in a timely manner.

#### 2008 - 2012: Harris County District Attorney

Senior Software Engineer

- Designed, developed, tested, and maintained conversion of legacy web sites, applications, and paper based systems to Rich Internet Applications using .NET technologies (C#, ASP .NET, MSSQL/T-SQL, and SSRS).
  Certain applications such as timesheet management and case explorer save 100s of man hours of work and increased productivity.
- Accumulated data from various case management databases, using SQL, to provide case activity related statistics including ADA assignments, statuses, physical file movements, and financials.
- Designed and developed Web Services and API modules to improve communication with in-house apps and third party software. Generated SQL views which assist in data sharing among inter-county agencies.
- Utilized PHP scripts, Visual Studio Macros, and SQL Stored Procedures to eliminate code redundancy.
- Developed software engineering documents (class diagrams, actor diagrams, sequence diagrams, and database schema diagrams) for all the applications developed.
- Engaged in vendor meetings to evaluate risks and costs involved in third party software implementations.
- Provided cost of in-house development (lines of code, development hours, etc) and maintenance versus OTS (Off The Shelf) products.

#### 2005 - 2008: Ultra Electronics

Software Engineer

- Utilized Object Oriented Analysis and Design, to design and develop a real-time forwarder/receiver module according to the specifications and requirements mentioned in military standards.
- Coded the forwarder/receiver module using C++ on Linux platform.
- Developed a MySQL database to store data ranges for the fields used from the military standards. This was used for validating the inputs and outputs of forwarder/receiver module.
- Developed PHP scripts to extract data from the database and format it in either CSV or XML format. This was used in the documentation for the module.
- Participated in Software Engineering documentation (Interface Detail Design, Software Architecture Design, Software Detail Design, and Software Programmers Guide).
- Participated in testing process by performing unit and system level testing of application.
- Assisted and mentored peers in providing development support and brainstorming throughout various components of the module.

#### Education

Bachelors of Science in Computer Engineering, 2005, Texas A&M University, College Station, TX

#### **Hobbies**

- Bicycling
- Hiking
- Listening to audiobooks
- Cooking